OpenClaw could really do everything.
It felt very uncontrolled and just a disaster waiting to happen.
LLMs in an agent harness, if they have an open check to do everything,
then like it's inevitable that they will eventually do something terrible.
It's just like evolution.
We came up with this idea of having an agent that's
within the controlled environment
and has access to the data, and you can have it investigate the issue
and troubleshoot it, and it has access to everything, right?
But one big constraint: it cannot output,
except for structured validated output.
So it can only output for a fixed vocabulary which you can verify
doesn't leak any data.
So those two agents,
they’re called Mulder and Scully, because they worked on the X-Files.
The AI Native Dev is a podcast for developers and engineering
leads at the cutting edge of AI and agentic coding.
Join your hosts, Guy Podjarny and me, Simon Maple,
every week as we chat with the most exciting voices in
AI and tackle the biggest questions facing developers today.
This is the AI Native Dev. ﻿
We just wrapped up two amazing days at AI DevCon in London.
But the great thing is that
we get to do it all over again in New York City this November.
You're absolutely right.
We're going to be back in the City that never sleeps on November 3rd and
fourth for more amazing sessions, really engaging hands-on workshops, and much more.
Yeah, all that great networking, partying, eating, and
drinking that you've come to expect from AI DevCon.
We think we have one of the best hallway tracks in the business,
and it's the perfect complement to our incredible speakers and presenters.
We'll both be in person and virtual,
with livestreamed access to all mainstage keynotes and talks.
Sign up right now for our Super Blind Bird ticket for just $100.
Only available for a limited time.
We're really excited to be headed back to the Big Apple, and we hope
to see you all there.
Hello, everyone.
Welcome back to the AI Native Dev.
Today we're going to have kind of a real world
case study talking about building agents within a company.
This will be within Cyera, which is a data security company.
We'll hear more about that in a second.
And to talk about that, we have Ori Shoshan, who has been one of the key leads
building that out.
So welcome to the show, Ori.
Thank you. Nice to be here.
So we're we're going to go a little bit in chronological order.
So just to give people a little bit
of a teaser around what it is that, that we're going to talk about.
I think you've built a really, really interesting and oftentimes
quite unusual platform for how to kind of work with agents.
That's a compliment.
It's like you're a little bit weird. It's good. Who wants to be normal?
And actually like a lot of many smart sort of small innovations and learnings.
I like you've built a different approach to harness engineering that starts
maybe like white lists tools versus blacklists them.
You have made some really smart infra investments and creating context graphs.
You, my agentic side, that has to have control over.
Just that sort of efficiency and part of it.
But that's been great.
And then,
you know, a lot of things, a lot of I loved the sort of small earnings around.
How do you permeate through the org?
You know, things like having people
take ownership of their agents or they care about it.
So and there's all these like great nuggets that we're going to dig into.
But instead of jumping into those, let's let's do this properly and kind of run
through a little bit of intros and origin story.
So first tell us a little bit about what is it that you do at Cyera.
And maybe a little bit about what Cyera is.
I'm a tech lead.
I work all across the world.
A lot of my work is focused on the DSPM product.
So that's the data
security, security posture management, as well as leading AI adoption.
as an AI data security company, we combine AI security.
Well, everybody wants to do a security.
Nowadays it's about.
And before I really boomed,
Cyera did that data security.
Right.
So we're a data security platform, meaning in a nutshell, we scan your data,
we find whether sensitive data is what type of data it is.
And then we let you do the really important stuff with it, like
deciding what your posture should be,
seeing what's exposed and how it's exposed and fixing that.
And in AI security also enabling you to allow
AI access to that data, but in a controlled and secure way.
Yeah. Which is
it's quite important to
to know where your sensitive data is and what you do with it.
If you want to build agents and let that agentic run freely,
because otherwise your risk leaks.
And if you're scared of data leaking, you're kind of paralyzed, right?
So it's it's really all about control. Yeah.
I love the agentic side. Yeah.
I love the the generally analogies and companies
that have have kind of grown up out of the problem
of the empowered workforce, which I think say,
and sort of data security posture management or sort of DSPM
fits that sort of mold where everybody gets to do a thing,
like everybody gets to create data in the cloud, you create those,
and then of course you have chaos because everybody's empowered to do that.
And so here, like income, a variety of solutions, many in the security space,
specifically in DSPM to like wrangle, where do I have data,
what's sensitive and what's not.
And then as we get into Agent Land, you know, agents are even less trusted,
you know, empowered entities that you're sort of running along.
And so they have to they have to be reined in even even more.
And so I love these kind of realities in which kind of solutions built for the,
for the prior,
but for the empowerment era actually very much sort of applied to this.
So yeah.
Oh, and about me, I forgot to tell about myself.
So I joined Cyera about a year ago for the other AIS acquisition.
So otherwise was my company.
I joined together with my team and my co-founder, Tomer Greenwald,
and together we lead AI adoption in Cyera
and and that sort of cool how it all connects.
And I guess just for, for context a little bit, that's how I got to know you.
So that was a part of the journey.
It was super interesting talk about sort of a
intent based access control and all that. I still believe in that, you know,
still happen, but, you know, love sort of
working out in the on the Cyera side, you know, collaborating there.
So, so, so this is sort of the background you're sort of in say
clearly data security company,
I think in the order of magnitude of sort of hundreds of engineers on it.
How how did you come so you're doing AI enablement or rebuilding it.
But I think your story was more about like scratching your own each.
Right. Right.
So it's 2026
and I'm, I'm sitting in my living room.
It's it's January.
So it's now 2026. We're still in 2026 right.
Like I don't know timelines are a little bit murky and the island but okay.
But it's January so we're like 5 or 6 months.
It's January 2026
and I'm I'm sitting in my living room and I'm doing something on my phone
and I ask myself, why am I using my hands to do this?
Why is it?
Is it not an agent doing it? For me, it's 2026.
It's not 125.
As we all know, in late November of
2025,
40 year models really took a leap, at least from my perspective.
I saw that I was able to build a primitive harness back
then, basically, you know, like a coding agent with, with some tests
and allow an agent to run much longer than it would have been able to before
with the just one generation of, of the frontier models before.
And then so few weeks
after that, I'm in my living room thinking how, why?
Why am I still doing things on my own?
I need a personal assistant agent to do it for me.
I'm building a house and all that, and I needed something to keep track of
of all of my commitments and
the argument I currently have with the contractor for the house.
And I really wanted an agent that would kind of
be like open claw, but I didn't like Open Claw at the time.
I think it was still called its previous name Cloud Bot or something.
But yeah, it went through phases.
It's like a teenager going up.
Yeah, but I didn't like that.
OpenClaw could really do everything. and anything.
It felt very uncontrolled and just a disaster waiting to happen.
because I kind of uri as or not not AI,
but LLMs in an agent harness,
if they have an open check to do everything, then
I feel like it's inevitable that they will eventually do something terrible.
It's just like evolution.
they will explore that path if it's the.
So I felt
like hooking up open cloud to all my stuff and having it manage my life.
My life is kind of precarious. Yeah, yeah.
So I started building out my own personal assistant,
which when I took a bit of a different approach
where instead of letting it do anything, I let it use a specific set of tools.
And then, I got it on WhatsApp and I would text with it
and it would be able to mention, well, where it's data is from.
And then I figured, actually, I would like to know it's not making stuff up.
Where is that sourced from?
And I figured, well, I actually have that data, I have that link.
So why don't I just have the harness, tell me,
well, where the what the source actually is.
Right.
And then eventually I realized, actually I want this at work to I mean,
why am I still getting slack messages and following on Salesforce.
And consuming tasks?
Yeah. Why don't I just know everything
all the time, but only the most important stuff.
And I want to have links to all of them.
Yeah.
I don't want to wonder,
is this something the model made up or is this backed by data?
Yeah. So this is I want to sort of unravel a few.
I love this sort of the personal to
to company paths on it, I think in part because you're, you're
kind of allowed to play a little bit more at home. Right?
As much as you are conscious about your sort of your own
kind of personal blast radius, you know, it's
sort of a little bit different than playing with sort of company data.
So, so as you, as you build those out, I think the first thing you talked about
is sort of this sort of containment of, of only
giving the agent some specific subset of tools on it, I guess.
How how crippling is that? Right.
Because some like clearly kind of from an AI or sort of AGI maximalist
path, it's a lot of like, you know, do not get in the way of intelligence.
Right.
Just sort of that it's that it's due the path, I guess.
How much was that felt that when you if you contain it
and you need to choose every time
which tools are available and maybe like a little bit of,
you know, there's probably still some leeway that you have to give it.
So what did you find was effective in terms of, of the lines?
So I, I would give it quite a bit of tools
and it would be the one tool I would not give.
It is bash, which is basically do whatever you want,
but it would have a bunch of other tools, for example, to read all my WhatsApp
messages and browse my email and but the
how do you say
the attack surface for each of them would be well known.
And I always leave an escape hatch,
so I could have.
So what you don't want is for an LLM
to try and use a set of tools and really be trying to do something else.
If it had bash, let it do whatever and then do something
that doesn't make sense just because it doesn't have the option.
That's a bad failure mode, because you may not notice
unless you actually look at the thinking tokens for the for the model.
Yeah.
So I always leave a tool that's, that's a sort of escape hatch,
whether that's doing something else. What.
But with a human in the loop or recording feedback.
So for the model to be able to tell you, I wanted to do this, but I have no,
no option to do that.
And then you go and add that and you very quickly arrive at a
50 at a set of 50 tools which the model has access to,
and it can do pretty much everything at once,
but you know that it can only do those things.
And structurally,
oh, I guess the hardness and forces that it can't do anything disastrous
like it can't send all my personal notes
to the contractor over email.
Yeah, yeah, that sounds like a negotiation
sort of sides or, maybe even like just sort of a goodwill.
So, okay,
let's come back to that a little bit in the context of the company on it.
The other piece you talked about is this notion of citations.
And so bring proof, I guess, is sort of the association
that comes to mind is what we see in Google, right?
Oftentimes today when you Google something, you get the A preview.
You've got sort of the the the equivalent of the blue links today.
Right. That talks about those references.
What's
is it just about sort of sourcing the information.
Is it similar
what you build for your, for the personal agent there, or is it something
a bit more distinct from that when you use it for your sort of
maybe kind of more elaborate because Google is very much
about like lookup of information.
So maybe a little bit more expected that the,
there will be a link for it.
Yeah.
So that that there is
I took inspiration from ChatGPT actually where they at some point
they started adding links next to where that the, the claim is sourced.
And the
the colony that I had was to know if the model is lying to me easily
because you get like a wall of text from an LLM and then you're thinking,
okay, well, which of this is based on fact and which of this is reasoning?
That's correct.
And which of this is reasoning that's incorrect.
And and it's really cognitively
exhausting to, to have to constantly evaluate that.
And it's one thing when you're working with a coding agent
and you're in an interactive session and you in the zone,
but for the personal assistant use case, you really don't want to be
paying so much attention, because that's kind of the the use case.
So I wanted.
So you don't care about
like you're fine for it to take more turns for the exchange
of getting the correct result at the end of it
because you're not sitting there supervising.
But if you get the wrong answer or you get something that that that can be
that can be, can cause substantial damage or at least waste a lot of time.
Yeah.
Well, I, I, I sort of assumed that, LLM is going to get
the model is going to get some stuff wrong.
And then I wanted to make it more obvious to me when that's happening.
And the way to do that is to have basically
instead of having the model be able to just produce prose,
it would be able to produce a structured output.
And that output is a, a set of blocks
where each block is a tuple of a citation and a source
reference, sorry, a claim and a source reference.
The source reference is a citation.
And then when the the output is rendered to me, I just get a list of.
Well, each claim is just a paragraph, say.
And then it has a a source reference and the link is automatically rendered.
And once I had that, I realized that I could actually use that
to do some context engineering and do a claim verification as well,
because LLMs tend to hallucinate more
or make the wrong conclusion when they have a ton of stuff
in the context and they end up paying attention. To that.
They're kind of in the dumb mode, you know, there's
sort of a lot of their sort of, context window is taken up by historical actions.
They might end up, you know, answering in the wrong answer.
And because they're kind of looking for a needle in the haystack.
Right. And they might look at the wrong needle.
Attention is the scarce resource, right?
Yeah. Attention is all you need.
So I realized, okay, now I have the ability to take each
claim and pair it with the raw data that supposedly behind it.
At least the LM says so.
And then I can take those two pieces of data and ask another model
with clean context, which has the claim and the data.
Is this claim supported by this data.
And in that mode of operation,
they tend to hallucinate a lot less because there's no noise.
So that reduces the amount of hallucinations overall.
So each claim independently tends to be.
More accurate that there is far fewer hallucinations.
And then if it is still a hallucination, I can just say that
the source and it's easy to tell if it made a citation.
That makes no sense, right?
It cited something completely irrelevant.
It does happen quite rarely.
Yeah, because the LLMs have the models have gotten quite good, right?
Yeah, I love the so I like that and I think I think a general kind of,
I guess a principle of working with multiple agencies
that any individual agent might hallucinate.
But if you layer on even one more to sort of, you know, review the work,
then then you reduce dramatically the sort of the chances of a hallucination.
And I think you're, you're you took it a step further
because you're even requesting the original kind of claimer
to, to create something in a slightly structured format on it.
So I, I like that.
So that's.
The escape hatch here was I let
him actually, go past go if they,
if they don't have a, a source reference, they can still produce a claim.
But it has to be marked as opinion.
And that's where all the reasoning goes.
So I know to take those with a grain of salt.
And the rest is what I use to evaluate I really like that.
I think oftentimes like the thing that is annoying when you're
sort of interacting and indeed, you know, the airlines have gotten better in this.
But, you know,
what used to be very annoying is it's not so much
that the LM makes a mistake,
but that it says these mistakes with such confidence on it.
So even just labeling it as like, hey,
I have proof of this and I do not, this is my opinion is probably useful.
I think it possibly even helps the LM to have that in the context
as the output, right?
So you're not so much to build on it. Yeah.
So let's move this back into work.
So you've learned and I imagine you sort of started
bringing this into the company before all of these things
was resolved on it, but I don't know.
But, as you, as you brought it into the company.
So how does this manifest in, in bringing into the company?
What did you have to set up and what does it look like today
when you run these agents inside the context of Cyera.
running it at home, I run it on a nuke
PC and I didn't even know it had a fan, but it turns out it has a fan.
And then bringing it into it
first I started running it locally, but I wanted it to run it 2447,
and I wanted it to have access to some things
and be unable to access some things which maybe my laptop can access.
Again.
My, my agentic side has to know, like what?
I have to know what's the possible failure mode and be okay with it.
Generally, like those are good tendencies
when you work at the data security company, right? that. Yeah.
So after you, you set up the kind of the,
so you handle the sort of the ops part of it. You're going to run this.
Now you have it in some sort of Cyera
owned or controlled agentic environment.
And then you mentioned that you have different agents that that can run on it.
So that's already like a bit of a distinction.
So before you kind of created this, this one agent to,
to be your personal assistant, you didn't need to probably like multiples of them.
I guess what I'm curious a little bit because I think a lot of
companies talk about like the, the blank slate problem.
Right? Or how do they get going?
What are what's a type of agent that got created.
We'll come back maybe a little bit to how you create agents on it,
but maybe just sort of talk a little bit about the use cases. So
within the
context of the company, how did you interact with the
with with yourself I guess, and with sort of users.
Because at the beginning it was like,
you know, to help you read slack messages and what are
what are the use cases that end up, you know, proving to be valuable?
Right?
So the first one was a type of personal assistant or its work
mode is chief of staff.
And then I
looked at making it more generally available, which initially did.
The obvious choice was to
make it into a slack bot to you can DM and tag in threads and.
An actual sort of chat interface. For it.
Yeah, just, you know, bring the bot to, to the, to where people work already.
And so the first use case is that the easiest one is to build.
Well and on call triage agent.
Well analytics pops up. There's a discussion about it.
You can ask the agent, hey, can you cause this
what's the impact.
Which tenants does it impact?
Stuff like that.
Very operational aka type of agent.
And this is you create the agent or someone creates an agent,
but then multiple people use it like this is a deviation from what you had before.
Before you were like there was a 1 to 1 one user to this agent.
Now there are multiple users to this agent, but
collaboratively or just like every every individual might sort of a
at the, the the bot and and get a response.
So early on really it was just every individual.
But there were some emerging properties out of that.
Well, the agent can read the thread so it can tell when it can see
the previous discussion.
It can see people
talking about using the agent, people complaining about hallucinations.
And then when you tag it, it sees the prompt, but it also sees the context.
So you might respond to something else as well. Okay.
So it's like it's like naturally a multi-person
kind of a multiplayer environment on it.
So it just sort of you got that for free.
So that was the interactive use case.
And then another use case was something else.
CTO Tomer proposed we have these channels on slack,
where's is a is and so on.
Might ask questions of product and R&D.
And you can answering
some of these questions can be done by looking at the knowledge base
the internal knowledge base, the public knowledge base, sometimes
the code, sometimes the questions.
And I think in many cases you just don't know exactly what you want to search for.
Kind of like searching on Google.
If you know the right keyword, you're going to find the answer.
But sometimes you first have to figure out what it is.
So agents are quite good at that.
Yeah, yeah.
But in this case like the, the the way that people interact with it.
Unlike the previous one is they don't add the bot.
They, they just ask the question in the channel.
And then the bot would ask them using an ephemeral message,
which is the type of message that shows up on slack when only you can see this,
like when you tag somebody in a channel and slack what says, hey,
this person isn't in the channel, should I add them?
That's an ephemeral message.
So the bot would ask you, do you want me to try and answer this?
And then if you click it, yes, it's going to answer publicly in the thread
for everybody to see.
And that's actually an adaptation because initially
it would just answer and it would annoy some people.
So I had it just start asking.
I figure just read it like a human, right?
If you ask for permission, if somebody wants you to, it's fine.
They won't be upset. Yeah, yeah. Cool.
Okay, so.
So, we kind of scattered a little bit over here
as I kind of ask different paths, but you have the bot.
It's running in your sort of slack.
Yeah.
You know, it has one use case, which is when you run mode of operation,
I guess when you sort of interact with it and it sort of answers
questions and one that it's sort of a proactively,
I guess, on a, on a schedule or just monitoring a channel.
So it reviews every message.
So it's just it's just monitoring the channel.
It's called ambient mode.
And it has a classifier that uses a cheap model to decide, is this a question?
Is this an announcement or something else?
And only if it's a question does it actually all fail to answer.
And there are a bunch of other use cases.
That's where the multi bot part comes into play.
So initially there was just one slack bot my own.
I called it Borg for the Star Trek reference.
That's the, you know, the cyborg hive mind.
And the thing about the platform is all the
would be agents of the platform
are going to share the same knowledge and all the feedback.
Yeah. Yes, they're going to all be assimilated.
So the joke was too good.
Plus I gave it a I took Cyera's.
If you go to a website you'll see we have this flying space pod icon.
So I put a little cute face on it and that's Borg.
So then the multi bots.
Right.
So I started out with just my own bot.
But the way that you would interact with these agents is by tagging them.
Right.
So now somebody else wants to create a bot.
The way for them to do that would be to create a new slack app
and give it a name and possibly a personality.
And this was something I did for a functional reason.
I just wanted
them to be able to customize the system, prompt the tooling, the context.
Right.
That the platform is aimed at engineers,
so they would potentially rewrite
the code that sets up the agent when it gets a prompt.
Right, and be able to do context engineering.
But a really nice side effect of that was
they ended up naming their agent and really feeling like it's their thing.
And it really helps adoption because it was no longer,
you know, I'm adding a bit of code to always agent.
It's my agent, which was really kind of my goal with this, for this
to be a platform that everybody on Cyera can use to build agent,
and they get the data infrastructure or the citations, the knowledge graph,
which maybe we'll talk about in a segment, but also the guardrails.
And to satisfy my, my need for.
For those controls. So so let's call okay.
So at this point of advanced down the story of it.
Now we have these bots running.
They're connected to slack.
They can do a variety of use cases which we you know we touched a couple.
We probably should sort of cover some more.
But then they don't you don't just sort of lump on all
the many use cases just to to Ori's Borg.
But rather now there might be you know, there are multiple agents.
I love the I love that sort of human insight of it,
which is once you name it, you care for it.
And it's like.,
It's fun to they make stupid jokes while they're answering.
Yeah, well, and you can do because you can kind of add your personality.
But then if you if you care for it, there's, you know, just like the yeah,
you get the investment within that.
But it also lowers the friction because people allow themselves to modify
because it's fine. It's mine.
I'm not getting in anybody's way.
So on one hand you kind of get that foundation.
Maybe let's go back a little bit and understand,
first, like maybe let's talk a little bit more about some use cases.
And then when we come back to understand how did that citation platform
kind of manifest.
Probably should talk about the knowledge graph there.
But how did that sort of come back?
But first let's come back a little bit to the to the use case example.
So like one I get its internal knowledge based lookup.
I think everybody relates to that. That's sort of a common use case.
You start talking about some some oppositions like root
cause analysis of it, maybe say a few words about that
and then you have a few other ops use cases.
All right.
So Cyera is a complex system. And
by by its very
nature data security deals with a lot of data.
Some of it takes quite a bit of time to scan just because of the sheer scale.
And so some operations can run for quite a while.
And that makes them how to troubleshoot.
I mean, if something ends in 10 seconds, you look at the operation, it's done.
Yeah.
So these on call or operation or troubleshooting
agents would have different triggers.
So some of them interactive.
Some of them are like the ambient answering questions agents.
But they would actually respond to alerts or
tickets from customers being open and do initial triage.
Some of them would do triage in terms of
assigning it to the right team based on what's in the in the ticket.
And then there's an entirely different class of agents still or slack bots.
But we have said a
the costs agent, which analyzes the cloud costs for Cyera
and then creates a report and root causes changes.
So it would see an increase in cost and try to attribute it
to increasing workload or changing the code
and help you sort of keep it under control over the time.
Like spring cleaning type housekeeping agents.
Yeah, exactly.
And then you also have agents which which have product managers, for example,
by looking at, feature
requests by customers or mentioned some slack for features
by customers and sort of help the PMC that there was a trend forming way before
it would have been detected otherwise, because before you had to have,
say an E or an A say, we need this feature and then it would need to
people would need to realize it's actually the same thing.
LLMs are good at finding those similarities and saying, hey, yeah,
I think this this is actually similar.
Pay attention here, in here and here. Yeah.
And this is like how many,
how many people have built agents because like these are.
This is sort of shared infrastructure.
But there are also very different agents that that people have built.
They share the same sort of, I guess, kind of patterns
around interfaces and the slack integration on it.
How like what is the result you mentioned developers are the ones
that are building the agents, but are there like five agents, 50
agents, 500 agents, like what's the what's the rough order of magnitudes?
It's around 30 agents,
built by about the same number of developers.
And the number of users is.
I don't have an exact number, but I imagine it's around
several hundred because it's it's not just the developers in the company.
Everybody use them.
Some even indirectly. cool.
So like I love the use cases.
And again there's sort of there, there they're very practical example
of, of of in general kind of building agents.
You know when people talk about sort of, you know, building
kind of enterprise automation,
but I love that it's, it's bringing bringing it into the heart, into slack.
But all of this is substantially enabled
by both the citation side and the tooling side.
Maybe actually, let's talk about the constraints first,
the sort of the tooling side.
So before we talked about how you kind of whitelist the tools versus blacklisting,
how does that work here.
Like all of these things, they need different tools.
Do you share the tools between the agents?
Do you define them like how does that work.
Right.
So the the agents all have a shared baseline of tools
and you can exclude some of them.
Or you can add custom tools to, to your agent
basically like skill like skills, except they have
how do you
say schema that gets validated and you can run code
and do the deterministic checks, for example.
Another example of an agent is an agent
that actually doesn't operate in slack, but it works on sentry.
So errors that sentry is an error management platform.
And then LS show up on sentry.
And we want to basically same thing as the slack agent right.
We want to triage them figure out the root cause if it's a bug, fix it
if it's an environmental issue.
So these are just basically settings as part of the configuration of
of the agent, which I guess you can think of
as a configuration of the harness, you know,
because this is the sort of the environment that you're exactly.
It is the harness. Yeah. It is the harness kind of with the tools.
Okay.
So that's fairly straightforward.
And I guess how, how often do people like
before you talked about kind of your mechanisms for knowing
that you need another tool because that's probably the, the piece that is
a, you know, like the dash dash dangerously accept.
Right.
Or sort of the dash dash is is also convenient, which is like,
I don't know what it's going to need, you know,
can you just just let it do its thing and, and trust it.
So I guess what's the what's the loop here.
You know, what's the interaction model and how often does it happen that people,
you know, like it fails because it doesn't have a tool and they come back to it?
Does it.
Does it typically sort of stabilize like they do that a few times.
And then generally
it kind of works or you know, what's the what's the experience there?
I think it's actually quite rare already from the
after the first few agents were well spun up because we,
we kind of plateaued around 60 ish tools that most agents have.
And that basically, Because the tools are shared between the different agents.
Right? Yeah.
So somebody adds a tool, all the other agents get
get it automatically, and then it just becomes possible.
So the way that we discover that the new tool tool is needed.
So the obvious choice is somebody would tell me that's quite bad
because in many cases people wouldn't tell you,
I wouldn't even know what to tell you.
And then there are a few other mechanisms.
So the citations they show up in line in the text,
whatever the interface is on slack or another platform.
And then what also shows up is the feedback mechanism.
So you get to thumbs up, thumbs down, and a few times down you can write why.
So that's the the obvious one. It goes.
And and when you when you specify feedback
that gets linked up against the original data
that backed this claim and not the specific answer.
So already the agent is learning just based on
if it queries the same data, it's going to see that in the context.
So you have that.
And then if somebody is talking in the conversation after the
the agent has responded
and he's like, man, I just wish it could, you know, give me a,
an update every 15 minutes so that that gets recorded.
Right. It's just on slack.
And then one, one
other mechanism that the platform has is a schedule mechanism.
So the agents can trigger have a trigger every schedule.
And the first one I added as an example really was the dream state,
which is to which is where the agent spins up every week and goes
and reviews all of its interactions, feedback,
and also the responses.
People go just around the answer and they might say something like that.
And then the dream state is going to go and submit
a pull request to improve the agent.
I like to joke that this part of the agent is the part that replaces me.
As it sort of chooses to sort of evolve it.
Cool.
So this is the loop, like this is the part in which it sort of optimizes it.
And in those context, the, the agent might come back and say, I need a new tool.
Or of course, it might sort of.
Change this one little thing. I forgot.
There's also a tool called
Submit Feedback, which is fully agent to submit feedback.
So if it's time to do something and it so it's looking at the tool list.
Right.
And it is. Honest for sort of some World Cup results on it.
And I don't know where those exist on it I need I need.
And then that gets saved.
And when the dream statements, it's going to see that in the context
of everything and possibly propose that change.
Got it. Okay.
And this is it's interesting that the tools are shared between the agents.
I guess I expect at some point in the future you might find yourself
sort of isolating and kind of further constraining the agents,
but just hasn't come up because you're already sufficiently contained.
So there is there is a bit of, divergence between them,
but it mostly has to do with functionality because not
all of the agents are only slack bots at this point.
There are other interfaces like the sentry one I mentioned.
Yeah.
And so so sending a slack message is a tool.
Right.
And going on about about control and and being
and the agents being constrained, the agent isn't able to select where it's
sending a message to that it gets triggered in a particular context.
And then it can call send message, but it only sends it to
the same thread that is unlocked for it.
It doesn't. It can't choose the destination.
So it can't make mistakes, you know, provided
that the harness only allows it to be triggered in the right context.
Right. But that's the deterministic bit.
Yeah, we know how to deal with that most of the time.
I think that very much is aligned with kind of my view. Right.
I think when you have the agent stack today, you have the models
that are kind of our operating systems we're building on.
And then on top of that, you have tools and context and harness,
and the context is kind of sandwiched between the sort of the tools
and the and the harness with the harness creating constraints.
And so that drives some determinism and some sort of security.
But then also the tools drive another, another set of constraints
and determinism.
So I like that you're sort of building that.
And I love also like as we had conversations about this.
It also sounds like you didn't set out to do this, but in practice
this also saves you substantial costs because you're talking about
like a fairly notable amount of sort of use here.
You know, it's scanning a whole bunch of data. It's doing all that work.
And I guess have costs stayed contained, like it hasn't really expanded.
Pretty much. Yeah.
The the actual usage is quite cheap relative to what I would expect.
And I think it is indeed, because it's, it's very structured
like the constraints keep it sort of on, on the rails.
Yeah.
Just setting up the, the, the knowledge graph which,
which will get into was quite expensive, but it was a one time class.
Is that so.
Let's, let's go there.
We sort of we've now sort of teased it up enough on it.
So okay.
And this also relates I think to the citations infrastructure.
Right.
So maybe talk a little bit about the knowledge graph and maybe
we can kind of slip into citations.
I know you have that sort of reviewer aspect of it.
So how does that work inside of the setup.
Yeah.
So that the knowledge graph is really so okay,
I didn't mention this, but quite early on when I had the idea of
maybe I want citations, maybe I want
I want all my data to be backed by a source reference.
I went and read, I am using, you know, here.
Yeah, yeah.
Using the AI version of read.
I, I did assisted reading using ChatGPT of a bunch of white papers
and all of these concepts that are provenance claim verification.
They've been explored quite fully,
over the years and especially in the, in the last year.
And it just made sense to put them together in this way, you know,
having all of your data backed by a source and then using that to do
claim verification and hooking up feedback into that.
It all felt natural.
It didn't come to me initially.
It came gradually. Yeah.
So the knowledge graph is an extension of that.
I was looking so
the obvious thing most coding agents or interactive agents,
you're going to give them access to data,
maybe to an LLM wiki, markdown files.
And they're going to go and explore.
Now, as a user, I know that sometimes they will not explore
all the things that they should be exploring.
And then you'll kinda down to
will they find a hint of something that pushes them in the right direction.
And Andre Karpathy
wrote about this, that having those links in the wiki helps them
find find the data they're looking for.
Right?
But that really lag in in the sense that using using a rag to build context
and just dumping that into the agent right off is no longer necessary
because agents are better at exploring nowadays.
Agent search versus rag is yeah.
So and and I see that.
But again, going back to my need for full control over agents, I,
I didn't like that sometimes the results would be inconsistent.
And so my way to solve that was okay, let's take all the data,
put it into a knowledge graph, a database, really with interconnections
between the entities, almost a rag, but then don't actually use it like a rag.
Let the agent walk the connections like it would an LM wiki on disk.
Just you can have many, many more pieces of data because now
it's indexed and the search is fast and finding relations is fast.
This is just sort of clarify
a little bit about what type of data might be in there.
Like, you know, this is like in the organizational context, right?
So it's anything from our code
slack messages, a particular exception popping
up, basically anything but
setting this up has quite a bit of cost
because extracting the entities and all that that goes through LLMs.
And then probably
the most important piece was working on data quality,
which is still very manual,
because if I just took all of sales data,
the relevant data, at least obviously not all the data,
and just stuck it in a knowledge graph, I think there would be mostly noise.
I don't know, maybe bots on slack sending alerts repeatedly?
It probably dwarves the amount of messages that humans send, which is the signal.
So figuring out the different data sources that we want
agents to have access to, how to model that in a graph.
So an account, an exception,
a service, those entities that that need to be in the graph
and then as the data is interested seeing well
where the noise is and actually going and cleaning that up.
So it took. Me well manually.
Manually. In bulk. But yeah.
Yeah.
But yeah, it took me a few weeks to, to finish.
Interesting because it was really bottlenecked on my own ability
to look at data.
I would of course look at the noisiest pieces.
Felt like you group by the source and the the origin
and and then and then clean that up.
But now we have about a million
or so pieces of data in the graph as opposed to many, many millions.
That would have been the other wise.
And the agents find surprising things,
which is a good sign, I think, as the the amount of signal in the.
So this is a so you gather data from a bunch of places and I imagine
like once that data is gathered and you kind of cleaned up the sources,
those are not repeatable, right?
You're now kind of keeping it up to date with, with new data
as it comes in of that shape, I guess, you know, kind of from,
from the relevant slack channels and the other, you gather that up
and then I guess, what are the tools that the agent uses to consult that?
This is like a data lake, right?
This is not what kind of a context layer
context graph, you know, you call it a knowledge graph.
Use whatever words you want and you say that the agent is able to kind of mine
that data in more efficient ways of doing it.
What what tools are make that possible.
So there are a few generic tools, an exact search.
So if it's looking for a particular service, for example,
it would use an exact search and find entities that have that,
that value in them.
So that maybe backing up a little bit.
So the Knowledge graph has episodes,
which is things that happened and got ingested,
and then it has entities and relations between those entities.
So if it's looking say at a particular
exception or a slack message in that slack
message, an exception, we have the entities that participate.
So in a system prompt which is shared to all the agents.
So there's a piece of the system prompt, a block of the system prompt
that's shared to all the agents and agents and explains
kind of how to walk the graph and, and what a radiant should behave like.
Yeah. And then you have another piece that's per agent.
So that shared piece explains
you should first use find exact if it makes sense.
If not use the semantic search.
Once you find the relevant entity, go ahead and walk the graph using
Find related.
So they're just finds that it would.
It's kind of like listing the directory and looking at interconnected entities.
So in the LLM wiki those would be the dimensions within the file.
And then once it does
that it has a bunch of specialized tools per data source.
Right.
So it might find an episode of a slack message.
And then it has a tool to read that slack messages thread
or look up more info, more messages by that person, and so on.
So those are the bulk of the tools, like just
just probably 5 or 6 tools per data source.
And then those the generic tools and those are all read only.
And there are a few right tools that are that involved with actually
solving problems, like performing a code review, posting a comment somewhere.
Submitting a pull request.
Cool, good.
So the so the context ref is is a great tool to basically spare
a bunch of this work during during the the agent run, and I love that.
Again, you sort of you, you were driven to create it
because you wanted determinism or, you know, like consistent success
when it should have the answer that part on it.
But it probably is a pretty big kind of time and money saver as well,
because now we don't need to, you know, kind of blunder its way,
you know, sort of through up through the data
and it doesn't read unnecessary data or it doesn't repeat that, which I guess
kind of comes back to you could just ask for structured data
or sort of cleaning it up. Yeah.
The goal was context engineering.
So that the setting it up so that the, the right data is, is in the context.
Yeah.
And I wanted to for example, if, if we go back to the very first use case,
it was finding a piece of data and finding what's related to it.
So if somebody is talking about an exception, I want to see the pull request
that introduced it.
I want to see the the exception, the logs
that the impact it has, and for the agent to reliably do that.
In my experience, it has to have a way to find those relations.
Right.
And they are there, like if I as a human can go and look at at a log line
and something like that and find them, then all I have to do is build a tool
that sets it up.
So when it calls, find related, those things just.
Pop up fine. Yeah, yeah.
I mean I think it's basically the conversation about structured versus
unstructured data.
And and I think what we're seeing is agents are, are so powerful
that you can give them highly unstructured environments.
You can give them bash and give them files and they will get a lot done on it.
But when you come to doing things at scale, reviewing large volumes of data
and performing actions repeatedly and you want to improve reliability,
I think there are there are multiple paths you can take.
There's the path of, you know, better instructing the agents
to eventually figure it out in like
it's all
I mean, I guess you can make significant progress, but it is
it's you're just playing with kind of make smarter individuals, right?
You know, in the elements.
But you're not actually sort of grouping them.
There is another path you have around sort of giving them.
Making the data more structured.
So making it easier for them to sort of
look up the right information at the right place.
And so that is that is helpful.
Of course, kind of adapt the context.
And then you can take it further and you can say,
okay, now that I have that structured data,
I can actually offload some of the cognitive efforts into tools
and, and run that, which makes a lot of sense because it's
basically how we operate with, with humans.
Yeah.
Actually really think about LLMs as humans.
I think that you just it's it's not it's really tempting
to think of them as computers, but really the only other thing in the world
which we know that, you know, if if they have the right training
and they have the right information, they generally do a pretty good job
of humans, but they're not infallible and neither are LLMs.
Right. So you're really helping them.
And it's so having these constraints and tools.
That's kind of how I work with myself as an engineer, I,
I try to set up my development environment so that the compiler yells at me
when I do something wrong.
I try to set myself up
so that my own mistakes are caught before they actually have an impact.
So I do that for my friend bug too.
Yeah.
No, I think, I think that that is a very effective way.
I think about that as well for a bit.
And there are somewhere in between humans and sort of systems.
You know, sometimes you use a system analogy and sometimes you.
Use eventually they'll just say kind of systems.
So, so cool.
So I just want to take stock a little bit.
Right.
Like at this point we talk about how you've gone from choosing
the citations based and sort of tools whitelisting approach to create the agent.
You created, the sort of shared repository
with infrastructure for everybody to create an agent.
And then you started by hosting yours and giving slack interactions to it
with both the kind of explicit and ambient
mode of interaction, which is pretty cool.
Basically who's who's who's in the driver's seat, right?
Like who initiates the conversation changes over there.
And then people started kind of evolving in and building their own agents.
I really, really like that sort of hack of like,
name it and it's yours and happy I build those out and and expand them.
And then we talked a little bit about the sort of efficiency component
to improve both accuracy, enable citations
and reduce costs in the process of that in the context graph.
So, you know, a ton, a ton of evolution on it.
I think we're sort of running out of time here a little bit,
but maybe just a couple of a couple of things that, you know,
when we were talking about this I found interesting.
One is when you when you teed this up, like in an organization, you're,
you're this, you know, engineering leader who is, you know,
building being an IC here, building a bunch of things, promoting it out.
But when you permeate it
through the organizations, you worked with, this AI captain's group on it.
So because oftentimes, again,
like affecting cultural change is a is a recurring need of it.
So tell us a little bit about that group and how does it work.
All right. So to to get started.
We we created a
Tomer and I created a small group called the AI captains.
And we basically picked a few people
who we already knew were more,
were interested in building agents and stuff like that.
And a little bit before, before that point,
we're talking December or something like that.
I built my first agent because I tried to accomplish a task.
It was classifying the amount of time it takes us to to fix a bug from
the pull request that introduced it to the pull request that fixed it.
And I tried doing it with a coding agent.
It had some success, but it was very inconsistent.
And at the scale that we are getting meaningful statistics
out of something so inconsistent was really hard for me.
So I figured, okay, let's try
and build an agent
and give it hints to keep it on the right path.
And sometimes you would see that.
You would see that the system hints leak into your context.
When you're working with a coding agent,
you would have the agent suddenly react to a system.
Hint it would say something like got it?
Command responses this way, so don't tell the user.
And and it accidentally tells you that.
And I saw what a massive difference it made to actually
constrain the agent and give it just the right tools it needs to do the job.
And of course, it takes a few iterations, right?
It's not a one hit wonder, but the consistency
and the quality actually improved.
So I wanted I felt like the best way to get other people to build
agents is to give them that sort of eureka moment as well.
So they would be like, Holy shit, I need to be writing more agents.
That's what I felt.
And so we formed that group.
If it was just 10 or 12 people initially.
And then we did like an agent workshop and it was all really simple.
And, and then with the, with these agents platform,
they would spin up their own agent and spinning up an agent
to get a carbon copy of Borg is really just, it's copy paste.
Right. It's a configuration file.
But once you do that you really think kind of the the power of it
and it lowers the barrier from those this unknown thing that's building
agents to, oh, there's a Python class I can modify.
Yeah.
Lower the easy enough.
So you share them.
You want
you want them to sort of see the light, and then you kind of
make it easy for them to get in the game, which I guess comes back to that fork.
The agent name of the agent don't change or his agent.
So yeah, just last.
Rate is lower. The barrier of entry.
And make it easy to,
to solve all the operational problems which are really not that interesting
whether you run your agent, what are the guardrails like?
Like having all that figured out, which are hard questions
to answer but not interesting from the application standpoint.
that.
I thought that was like an effective,
sort of simple, repeatable, but sort of effective way to, to promote things.
I think it worked really well.
And, and itself it, it became self sufficient
to like once those fails, people really adopted it.
Some of them became massive champions of it within the organization.
And I reinforced that.
So I would tell people, you don't need my code review.
You can ask those people. Yeah.
And there are the guardrails.
They do require my code review, but I added some of them to
be the code code owners for that as well.
The guardrail is really how we're keeping Claude or other
coding agents from, you know, really going to crazy
and removing removing some of the safeties.
So I would really reinforce that and kind of
my approach has been all carrots and no stick.
Just make it really easy, make it safe.
Really making it safe is making it making it really easy.
It's another way of doing that. Yeah.
Avoid, concerns about blast radius and sort of concerns.
So you just.
Didn't exactly make it so people don't have to worry
and reinforce it when somebody, you know, somebody is effective
and he takes the the reins be like, good.
Yeah, keep going and point people out and.
Sort of celebrate the successes.
And I think the, the, the last two case, I wanted to to just sort of like,
get from you as we, as we, as we sort of maybe like, wrap up a little bit
after that is, is how you kind of dealt with secret data.
So, like,
you're in the world of data security, a lot of that data is quite sensitive.
And so on one hand,
like as a company, you need to deal with the fact that you have
you need to secure and sometimes troubleshoot problems
when things don't work on data, that is that you're not supposed
to be able to see, or that maybe like there's
a specific individuals that have been under NDA or whatever
it is, have the right kind of, you know, clearance to be able to sort of
see that data.
So, so I love you've also used agent a little bit
to like export your intelligence and sort of importing the data on it.
So maybe tell us a little bit about that use case
which found like a good novel use for for agents.
Yeah.
That's one of the use cases I think that actually we weren't
really able to think about before agents were a thing
that everybody in Cyera are thinking.
And before you started building affinity to like, what is this thing? Right.
Yeah.
Because okay, I'll talk about it then it will be obvious.
in some cases you could have, for example, the, the on call triage agents,
they have access to, to all the data and you have access to the same data.
And it's easy to see and it's easy for them to troubleshoot.
And it's easy for you to see that it's correct.
But in in other cases, you may be working in an environment
where you're not allowed to see the data or even access the data
for regulatory reasons or because of customer commitment.
But obviously there are still bugs, so you do need some way to deal with that.
And up until we had agents, really that the only way to deal with
that is to get a particularly small group and pre-approved
group of people who can see the data and they can then go and troubleshoot it.
But, as the company, as company, as a company
like, grows larger and larger, I mean, we grew quite quickly.
I think a year and a half ago we were massively smaller.
You may need more people than that small group.
Right.
And how do you do that then?
So We came up with this idea of having an agent that's
within the controlled environment and has access to the data,
and you can have it investigate the issue
and troubleshoot it, and it has access to everything, right?
But But one big constraint: it cannot output,
except for structured validated output.
So this troubleshooting agent has access to everything.
But then it can only output for a fixed vocabulary
which you can verify doesn't leak any data.
Yeah.
And then so it does its investigation outputs in the fixed vocabulary.
And then that goes that can actually go out of that parameter
to other people who are not approved.
Because now, you know, nothing sensitive was was sent out.
And then we have another agent which reads that data
and has access to the code and all of the wider
availability data, and can put together an explainer for humans backed on that.
Other agents conclusions.
So those two agents, they’re called Mulder and Scully,
because they they worked on the X-Files.
Hey everyone!
Hope you're enjoying the episode so far.
Our team is working really hard behind the scenes to bring you the best guests,
so we can have the most informative conversations about agentic development,
whether that's talking about the latest
tools, the most efficient workflows, or defining best practices.
But for whatever reason, many of you have yet to subscribe to the channel.
If you're enjoying the podcast and want us to continue to bring you
the very best content,
please do us a favor and hit that subscribe button.
It really does make a difference and lets us continue to improve
the quality of our guests and build an even better product for you.
All right, back to the episode. ﻿
this is basically a way of having kind of two agents talk
across a wall, you know, when you sort of can see the data.
And I guess the result of that is you can troubleshoot issues a lot more
efficiently with because expertise varies like the people around it.
You can have somebody on a,
on a team that doesn't have access to the data program.
The agent
with all of the knowledge of that team and how to troubleshoot and examples and
and then the agent goes and does that in, in a controlled environment.
And the feedback is, is fixed and safe.
And then going back to that the escape hatch thinking
the controlled agent can still output to the
small list of people.
If it does need to say something that it can't say using the vocabulary
it goes and outputs that free text to that group, and then we can go
and expand the vocabulary after human review by the approved people.
So yeah, it. All comes together.
Yeah. Just kill those people. So I thought that was very cool.
And I, I feel, you know,
not just about confidential data, but also when you think about on prem support,
when you think about all these paths, I think that's very compelling.
In many use cases where you can't you just can't have the data go out,
but you still need to operate.
So thanks for sharing all this.
Like I love the journey on it.
I mean, sort of we told it, I felt like the sort of the
the destination and all those insights are super useful.
But I think the way to achieve like the sort of the journey to sort of iterate
and how how did you learn and what did you add later,
I think is, is, you know, just as educational for
in a lot of organizations that are going through that process.
So thanks for sharing.
And I guess just before we wrap up, I'll ask you, what are you excited
to, to do next for, for this whole journey?
So I think right now that the most exciting thing is working
on our code harness, coding harness that uses all of that infrastructure.
But honestly, I feel like
if you ask me two weeks from now, it might be something else,
because there are a lot of ideas that we couldn't
have had before like this, this confidential information agent.
I don't think I could have thought of that a few months ago,
before I had internalized thinking in terms of agents.
So I'm really just excited about that.
It's sort of a meta assignment.
It's not a particular thing I want to build, but I'm I'm.
Excited new ideas.
To to be able to execute on them so quickly.
Right.
Because now building an agent, once you have all this setup is, is really easy.
Getting it access to the right data like this confidential agent
sounds like possibly a heavy lift with lots of moving parts.
Two days. Yeah, right. That's nuts.
It's not just LLMs, but having all this set up and also,
honestly that we're a data security company
and like, you know, what data you have and and where it is
and you, you can let the agents access it and know they're not going to go wild.
Yeah I think that's really, really important.
And if I can just give one tip to,
to the audience,
since having AI adoption is really about adoption, it's
about making people adopted
this new mode of thinking and building agents.
So I will recommend trying to do it with a platform engineering approach.
That's why I went all carrots, because you really trying
to get people to adopt a new type of agency for themselves.
And you can't tell them to do that.
They have to internalize it.
So you have to lower the bar and make it look enticing and make it.
There's.
Yeah.
And I would love to say I thought about all that before,
but it's kind of in hindsight.
I think it makes a lot of sense.
And I think I think we've learned a lot
from the DevOps transformation and the value of the paved roads.
And, you know, you you enable that.
And I think the other advantage I'll sort of highlight is that it
it it helps people along on the journey
because you've paved the road and it's easy for them,
but it also still allows them to sort of bushwhack their way
kind of along the along the side and maybe find shortcuts.
And so most people will just opt for the paved road,
and then the few that goes to the side,
some will regret and come back, and then some will will find a new path.
And so there's an opportunity for learning.
Yeah. Because if you.
If you just sort of centralize and you constrain as opposed to like
you just work with the sticks,
then the result of that is, is you're saying, well,
it's only these sort of smart people in the platform team.
They're the only ones who can innovate, and the rest just sort of apply it.
And so enabling a paved road, but allowing someone to go to the side.
Is a is a powerful path.
I think it's it's even it's easier to have that mode of thinking
as, as the platform team for this because agents are new to everybody.
Right.
So it didn't require any mental gymnastics
on my part to assume that there are things I didn't think about.
Cool.
Well, thanks a lot for coming on the show.
Love what you've been building.
Looking forward to explore the futures.
And thanks everybody for tuning in, and I hope you join us for the next one.
The AI Native Dev is brought to you by the package manager for skills and context.
Your hosts are Guy Podjarny and me, Simon Maple.
Our producer is Tom Dowler.
The AI Native Dev is not just a podcast, it's a community.
And we host monthly meetups at the Tessl offices in central London.
Visit Tessl.io forward slash community to learn more and I hope to see you there.